ROSTYSLAV HANNOTSKYI

Senior Software Engineer

CONTACT

- superdevstar1218@gmail.com
 - +1 914 265 2104 🤳
- github.com/superdevstar1218 🗇
- https://long-cell-6997.on.fleek.co

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science University of Warsaw April 2013 - March 2017

SKILLS

Java, JSP, J2EE, JDBC, Maven, Gradle,Spring MVC, Spring boot, Struts, Java Swing, Java Fx HTML / CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery PHP, Laravel, Symfony Node.js, NestJS, Express.js, GraphQL

React + Redux, Angular, Vue, React Native

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, DB2, MongoDB, Airtable, Firebase

Tomcat, Kafka, Elastic Search, Solr, Lucene

SOAP, RESTful APIs AWS, Azure, GCP, Microservices Git, SVN, CI/CD, Docker, Heroku, Jira, Bitbucket, Scrum/Agile NetBeans, Eclipse IDE, VS Code,

PHP Storm

SUMMARY

Senior Java Full Stack Developer with over 6+ years of experience in software design, development, implementation and software engineering which also includes integration, maintenance and testing of various client/server, and web applications.

Skilled and experienced in Core Java, Spring (and frameworks), Hibernate with JPA, Spring mvc, Spring Data, Rest services, JSON, Junit 4.0, mockito framework.In-depth knowledge of patterns and practices, including Object Oriented Programming, MVC, REST architecture, Agile, Test Driven Development (TDD) and Continuous integration. Strong working knowledge on modern build tools and continuous integration framework.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack developer

Mettle

lan 2022 - Dec 2022 / Remote

- Contributed to the development of Mettle, a standalone SME challenger bank launched by RBS that provides a current account, instant invoicing, and the ability to add receipts to transactions and track expenses from a mobile app.
- Extended and maintained existing and created new microservices which fit the event sourcing architecture of the Mettle platform.
- Added features to the React Native mobile banking application.
- Migrated the event stream to AVRO so we could implement continuous deployment.
- Extended the automated test suite by introducing consumer-driven contract tests (Pact).
- Created an interactive dashboard to track business and team OKRs.

Full Stack Java Developer

Callsign

Oct 2019 - Dec 2021 / Remote

• Fully-involved in the architecture, design, and development of new products and features.

- Wrote a new, modern version of the Callsign dashboard from scratch in React. I managed to phase out the old version of the product iteratively by working closely with product designers to rethink and redesign features and move them to the modern view.
- Created an extended version of the Callsign Admin REST API which provides a standard interface for onboarding organizations and users into Callsign.
- Contributed to Callsign On Premise (OP). We were tasked to extract part
 of the platform to allow deploying it on clients' premises so that
 enterprises are in control of their transactional data.

Full Stack Developer

Ministry of Justice, UK

Jun 2017 - Sep 2019 / Remote

- Ensured the divorce microservices fit in the overall high-level design of the reform program. This involved regular meetings with the program architects and communicating design decisions with team members.
- Created low-level design documents, selecting the right tools and technologies, and made sure that the software released to the public was as robust and secure as it could be.
- Removed technical impediments and owned the overall sprint outcome.
- Created new and extended existing microservices to deliver features to citizens, government officials, and solicitors.
- Led the digital divorce team.

Full Stack Developer

Self-Employed & Remote, Freelance

May 2016 - Apr 2017 / Remote

- Worked on 4+ projects using Spring frameworks, MERN & MEAN Stack, including the website development from the scratch.
- Developed the website, integrated with full-text search engines such as Solr
- Designed, architected, and implemented scalable cloud-based web applications using AWS, Microservices & GCP, etc.